牢记“人格”
Remember the "Personality".
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
弗拉门戈舞蹈史上最伟大的人
greatest name of all times of flamenco dance...
塞诺拉·费扎
Senora Feza.
-奥莱！-当然，奥莱
- Olé. - Sure, Olé.
你认为内芙拉被说服了吗？
Do you think Nevra was convinced?
绝对的
Absolutely.
真是太令人信服了 她正在跟踪我们
So much for been convinced. She is following us.
被杀的三个人
The three man who were killed...
他们在我们网站上的清单上
they were on the list in our website.
你知道这意味着什么吗？
You know what this means don't you?
“狗杀手”正在关注我们的网站
"Dog Killer" is following our website.
你以为你在做什么？
What the hell do you think you're doing?
这就是那个女人既没有被强奸也没有结过婚的原因
That's why the woman neither got raped nor she got married.
但是我们知道她已经结婚了 所以我决定去了解……
But we knew she was married. I decided to follow her to find out...
她要去哪里，谁在强迫她说谎
where she was going and who was forcing her to lie.
那时你就出现了
That's when you came into the scene.
-你怎么知道的？-我想看看这个地方
- How did you find out? - I wanted to see the place.
如你所见，房子已经消失了
As you can see, the place has gone back in time.
内芙拉·埃尔玛斯
Nevra Elmas.
内斯林夫人的女儿
Mrs Nesrin's daughter.
不要再打这个电话给我
Don't call me on this number again.
实际上，最好忘记这个号码
In fact, it is better if you forget this number.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
现在，尊敬的检察长
Now, the honourable D.A...
谁一直在纠缠我的案子，为什么？
who has been messing with my case and why?
这是第一
This is number one.
还有第二……
And the number two...
谁让菲鲁兹回到案件调查中来的？
who specifically reinstated the man to the case whom I removed?
谁在处理这些事？怎么回事？
Who is running this case? What's going on?
内芙拉！
Nevra!
-雷汉-谁是雷汉？
- Reyhan. - Who is Reyhan?
[你把礼物藏起来了吗？]
[Did you hide your gift?]
[是的，你想从我这里得到什么？]
[Yes. What do you want from me?]
[见我]
[To meet me.]
[何时何地？]
[When and where?]
[很快 就在附近]
[Soon and nearby.]
[我怎么知道是你？]
[How will I recognize you?]
[我手里还会有另一件礼物]
[There'll be another gift in my hand.]
[它是什么？]
[What is it?]
德瓦！
Deva!
爷爷
Grandad!
把那个东西关掉
Turn that thing of.
今天因为你 我发生了一件很糟糕的事情
Something really bad happened to me today, because of you.
怎么了?
Why? What happened?
木已成舟 不关你的事
What's done is done. None of your business.
爸？
Dad?
这是怎么回事？为什么朝他大喊？
What's going on? Why are you shouting at the boy?
他把汽车的日志放在其他的地方
He put the car's logbook in a wrong place.
我找了一早上
I wasted my morning looking for it.
那是什么大事吗？我以为发生了什么
Is that what it was? I thought something happened.
最后你找到了吗？
Did you find it anyway?
是的，我找到了
Yes, I did.
但为时已晚了
But it was too late.
- 非常感谢- 非常感谢
- Thanks. - Thank you.
我们找到她了吗？
Did we find her?
我的意思是，这就是塔亚尔强奸的女孩吗？
I mean, is this the girl whom Tayyar raped?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是即使我们找到她，也为时已晚
But even if we found her, it is too late.
为时已晚
Much too late.
雷汉，等等！
Reyhan, wait!
我可怜的孩子，你怎么能结束自己的生命？
My poor baby, how could you take your own life?
她还是个孩子
She was still a baby.
妈妈，你不记得雷汉吗？
Don't you remember Reyhan, mum?
亲爱的，我不记得她了
No darling, I don't remember her.
她是你的朋友吗？
Was she your friend?
我们是同学
We were classmates.
但是我几乎抹掉了所有与坎布拉相关的记忆
But I erased almost every memory related to Kambura.
我什么都不记得了
I don't remember anything.
但是当我看到照片时，我以为“我认识这个女孩”
But when I saw the photo I thought "I know this girl."
“这是雷汉”
"This is Reyhan."
她比我大一点
She was slightly older than me.
是的，她比我大2岁
That's right, she was 2 years older than me.
你还记得什么？
What else do you remember?
我不知道
I don't know.
不太清楚
It is not very clear.
我不认为雷汉自杀与塔亚尔的死有关
I don't think Reyhan committing suicide is linked to Tayyar's death.
她于1996年自杀
She committed suicide in 1996.
塔亚尔于2008年去世，这之间存在12年的时间
Tayyar died in 2008.There are 12 years in between.
烧毁塔亚尔房屋的人，无论是乌福克还是其他人
Whoever burned down Tayyar's house, be it Ufuk or somebody else...
不会等12年才报仇
wouldn't have waited 12 years to take Reyhan's revenge.
无论如何，目前尚不清楚为什么雷汉自杀
Anyway, it is not yet clear why Reyhan had committed suicide.
我们离开小镇两年后，她自杀了
She committed suicide 2 years after we left the town.
她当时几岁？
How old was she at the time?
她比我大2岁
She was 2 years older than me.
那让她14岁
That makes her 14.
她为什么要这样做？
Why would she do such a thing?
最近15年有11例女性自杀案
There are 11 cases of female suicide in the last 15 years.
日期更接近塔亚尔被谋杀的时间
The dates are closer to the time when Tayyar was murdered.
如果发生强奸案，应该是这其中一例
If there is a case of rape it's got be one of them.
我认为我们应该首先研究这些文件
I think we should start by digging into these files.
这些女孩我都不认识
I don't know any of these girls.
不好意思
Excuse me.
喂？
Hello?
好了，让我们假设这个案例直接与你相关
O, K, let's assume that this case is directly linked to you.
你一定认识受害者或凶手
You must know the victim or the killer, or whatever you want to call them.
所以，可能你过后就记起来了，就像你记得雷汉
So, it may come to you later, just like you remembered Reyhan.
告诉我何时何地
Just tell me when and where.
别担心，没人会知道
Don't worry, no one will know.
你为什么不相信我？
Why don't you try to trust me?
如果你问我，这件雷汗案是浪费时间
If you ask me, this Reyhan case is waste of time.
再给我一天时间
Just one more day.
如果我没有任何进展就回伊斯坦布尔
If I don't get a break I'll go back to Istanbul.
好的，你请便吧，与此同时我来调查这些文件
O.K, whatever you say. Meanwhile I'll go through the files.
好 我先走了
O.K, I've got to go.
你好吗？
How are you doing?
我不知道
I don't know.
你要从哪里开始？
Where are you going to start?
我先去看看她的房子
I'll check her house first...
还有我记得她的地方
and the place I remember her from.
学校
The school.
我妈妈认识我们的老师 他退休后在这里定居
My mum knows our teacher. He settled here after he got retired.
我会跟他谈谈
I'll talk to him.
我不知道
I don't know.
你呢？你会回到伊斯坦布尔吗？
How about you? Will you go back to Istanbul?
其实，现在我就在这里，我想请你妈妈同意……
Actually, now that I am here, I can ask your mother's permission...
让你嫁给我
to marry you.
但她可能会问我是做什么工作的
But she'd probably ask what I do for a living.
我对她说：“我是失业记者大军中的一名步兵”
And I say to her "I am a foot soldier in the army of unemployed journalists".
这就是为什么我应该先回到伊斯坦布尔找到工作后再来
That's why I should go back to Istanbul and return when I get a job.
-爸爸你还好吗？-还行
- Are you alright dad? - So so.
你还在对日志的事情生气吗？
Are you still upset about that logbook thing?
不，不，已经无所谓了
No, no. It doesn't matter anymore.
-对不起 -好的，好的
- I am sorry. - Yeah, O.K.
你小时候对我也这样，还记得吗？
You used to do the same to me when I was little, remember?
你曾经为了很小的事情就对我大喊大叫
You used to put me through hell for the smallest thing.
什么也没有变
Nothing has changed.
有一次我弄坏了电视
Once I broke the video.
如果不是我妈妈的话我会被我赶出去
If it wasn't for my mum he would've kicked me out.
他很生气
He was so mad.
这只是一台电视，一台机器
It was just a video, a piece of machinery.
我有权生气 我告诉过你不要胡闹
I had the right to be mad. I told you not to mess around with it.
我们新买的
We'd only just bought it.
我想好好看一部电影，但发现它坏了
I wanted to enjoy a good movie only to find out that it wasn't working.
我才刚开始分期付款
I'm only just begun to pay the instalments.
你知道修复它需要花多少钱吗？
Do you know how much it cost to get it fixed?
你的记忆力真好
You have such a good memory. It is scary.
你可能还记得当时要看的电影是什么
You probably still remember what the movie was.
我当然记得了
Of course I do.
克莱默vs克莱默 我当然记得
Kramer vs Kramer. Of course I remember.
你是怎么记得住所有这些的？
How do you remember all this?
我永远不会忘记
I never forget.
现在我还记得 我记得过去的所有事
Now I remember. I remember the old.
现在有更好的电影了 贝尤鲁vs贝尤鲁
Now there is even a better movie out. Beyo?lu vs Beyo?lu.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think? Is it nice?
我很高兴我弄坏了电视 我真棒
I am so glad that I broke that video. Well done to me.
-我走了-去哪里？
- I am off. - Where to?
我要和努赫特小姐一起度假
I am going on a vacation with Miss Nükhet.
和努赫特一起度假吗？
Going on a vacation with Nükhet?
他跟那个女人有什么关系？
What is he going to do with that woman?
“那个女人”爱我
"That woman" loves me.
她对你的了解足够使她爱你吗？
Does she know you well enough to love you?
因为爱一个你不认识的人很容易
Because it's easy to love someone whom you don't really know.
我既了解又爱你
I both know and love you.
让我们看看她是否也能做到
Let's see if she can do the same.
他在旅行时会与努赫特做什么？
What is he going to do with Nükhet on vacation?
我们会整夜做爱
We'll make love all night.
他说什么？
What did he say?
你知道吗
Do you know...
有一天，他们会把我们放在这样的罐子里
one day, they'll put us in jars just like these...
科学家会说“曾经有种叫做’人类‘的物种“
and scientists will say "there used be a species called "human"...
但是现在已经灭绝了
but now it's extinct.
过时了
It became obsolete.
我们可能没什么可放入罐子里了
We may have nothing left to be put in jars.
我们前进的道路上，人类将把自己从历史中抹掉
The way we're going, the human race will wipe itself off the history.
说的也对
That's correct too.
我们第一次达成共识
For once, we are on the same side.
首先，感谢你能来
First of all, thanks for coming Ate?.
不客气，我认为这已经变得不重要了
You're welcome. I thought this has got to be important.
否则，为什么托尔加局长要称我为小丑？
Otherwise, why should superintendent Tolga call a clown?
-阿提斯，听着……！-不，不
- Ate?, look...! - No, no.
你是对的
You're right.
我已经当小丑多年了，但是现在已经结束了
I've been a clown for years. But it is over now.
好吧，我听着
Well, I am all ears.
好的
Alright...
你知道连环杀手的事
you know that serial killer thing...
高层有人干预案件
there is someone at the top interfering with the case.
我不知道那是谁
I can't find out who that is...
也不是他们这样做的原因
neither the reason why they're doing it.
我知道你有关系
I know you have connections.
你能帮我找到这个人吗？
Can you help me find this man?
-我可以试试-很好
- I can try. - Fine, good.
但是有一个条件
But with one condition...
结案之前不能有爆炸新闻
no breaking news until this case is solved.
成交吗？
Is that a deal?
成交
O.K.
好，就这么定了
O.K, it is a deal.
让我问你一件事
Let me ask you something.
说吧
Go ahead.
你怎么相信我
How come you trust me?
内芙拉
Nevra...
内芙拉信任你
Nevra trusts you.
我相信内芙拉
And I trust Nevra.
还有一个问题
One more question.
你有权感到焦虑
You have all the right to be anxious.
我会和你分享另一个信息
I will share another information with you.
我带齐东西了吗？牙刷，袜子
Have I got everything? Toothbrush, socks.
我还应该带本书
I should take a book too.
我们从图凡·埃里波尔的尸体中找到了证据
We seized evidence from Tufan Elibol's body...
那个曾被凶手用来做挡箭牌的人
whom the killer used to throw us off the case.
你真的有证据吗？
Do you really have any evidence?
你怎么看？
What do you think?
骗人的吧
It is a hoax story.
我们称之为“鼓励错误的奖励”
Let's call it "bonus to encourage mistake".
这样比较好
It is better this way.
这意味着凶手自寻死路
It means that the killer shot himself on the foot.
我可以向你保证，他很快就会被抓
And I can assure you he will be caught very soon.
我刚刚在看连环杀手的新闻发布会
I was watching the press conference about the serial killer.
你要说些什么吗？
Were you about to say something?
不，我要走了
No, I am going.
爷爷
Grandad!
你不想在离开前见妈妈吗？
Don't you want to see mum before you leave?
我很着急 你可以替我给她一个吻
I am in hurry. You can give her a kiss for me.
妈妈 爷爷要走了
Mum! Grandad is going.
至少告诉我们你要去哪里？
At least tell us where you are going?
我要去坦桑尼亚的野生动物园
I am going to Tanzania for safari.
我现在要做什么？
What am I going to do now?
我从没听到过
I never heard that.
可能是，我听过，但没当回事
May be, I heard but never listened.
他们如何找到证据的？
How can they find evidence?
我用漂白剂
I washed him thoroughly...
彻底洗过他的尸体……
with bleach.
还是我根本没洗？
Or did I?
他们如何找到证据？
How can they find evidence?
是的 我洗了他
Yes, I washed him.
我洗了吗？
Did I wash him?
没洗 洗了
No, I didn't. Yes, I did.
不可能 我明明洗了尸体
It is not possible. Because I washed the body.
我没洗
I didn't wash it.
为什么？
Why?
太晚了 已经到头了 他们抓到我了
It is too late now. It is the end of the road. They got me.
无能为力了
Nothing you can do.
不，等等 不要着急
No, wait. Don't rush.
门口没有警察
No cops at the door.
他们应该已经在这里了
They should've been here by now.
他们可能正在路上
They may be on their way.
已经过去好多天了
It's been so many days.
他们应该已经到了
They would've been here by now.
我正要去度假
I was about to go on vacation.
放松一点，读一本好书
Relax a bit and read a nice book.
我已经读过这本了
I've already read this.
我才刚看过
I've just read it.
好
O.K.
所以就是这种情况
So, this is the case.
随它去吧
Just let it be.
我再去杀一个
I'll go and do another one.
这个已经死了
This one's already gone.
这是什么？
What is this?
不，这个在伊斯坦布尔
No, this one is in Istanbul.
还有谁？
What else?
也不是这个 去死吧
Not this one either. F..ck off to hell.
是的，这个可以
Yes, this one will do.
工作与娱乐合二为一
Business and pleasure in one.
杀光他们
Kill them all.
我觉得这个可以
I think this one will do.
你说什么？可以吗？
What do you say? Is it O.K?
可以
This will do.
你在跟我讲话吗？
Are you talking to me?
那么，我们去哪里？
So, what are we doing?
我认为如果去温泉，会有一群老人
I thought if we go to a spa, there'll be herds of old people...
像浮标一样漂浮在水中
floating in the water like buoys.
很无聊
It is boring.
我想出了一些不同的东西
I came up with something different.
-在哪里？-是个惊喜
- Where? - It is a surprise.
好 没问题
O.K, that's fine.
但是你知道真正的惊喜是什么吗？
But do you know what the real surprise was?
当你今天早上给我打电话告诉我……
When you called me this morning to tell me that...
我们马上出发 那才是真正的惊喜
we are leaving right away. That was the real surprise.
你让我措手不及
You caught me off guard.
因为昨天发生了一些事情
Because something happened yesterday.
我决定了
And I made a decision.
不应该搁置生命中的任何一件事
You should never put anything on hold in life.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我的风筝被困在树上
My kite got stuck on a tree.
风筝？
Kite?
你是说你一直在放风筝吗？
Do you mean, you've been flying kites?
当然是的
Yes, of course.
你真是个令人惊讶的人
You are such an amazing man Agah.
我认为我不自大 可能有一点点
Without being big headed, I think I am, a little bit.
她现在干什么？
What is she doing now?
我不知道她已经进去十分钟了
I don't know. She has been in there for 10 minutes.
我去看看她在做什么
I'll find out what she is up to.
听着菲鲁兹
Listen Firuz...
你犯了一个错误 你被内芙拉看到了
you made a mistake by getting caught by Nevra.
然后我做了什么？
And what did I do?
我接受了你的错误 然后加以纠正
I took your mistake and blew it out of proportion.
这个错误变得如此之大，但已经解决了
And that mistake grew so big, it became legit.
但这并不意味着每次都会发生相同的情况
But it doesn't mean that same will happen every time.
幸运的是我们堵住了裂缝
Luckily we sealed the crack.
我不想再看到裂缝
I want no more cracks Firuz.
我不想再看到有任何泄露的迹象
I don't want any more leaks.
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
如果我的房子被水淹了，你将是第一个被淹死的人
If my house gets flooded, you'd be the first one to drown.
好的，塞米尔先生
O.K Mr Cemil.
我已经做了多年了，但我还没有想明白
I've been having this done for years but I am yet to decide.
我想知道一天结束的时候是谁感觉更好
I wonder who feels better at the end of the day.
我还是它们？
Me or them?
我想我进入这个世界是为了养活水蛭
I think I came into this world to feed the leeches.
是的，谢谢 谢谢
Yes, thank you. Thank you.
是的，谢谢
Yes, thank you.
什么都不懂是件好事
Not understanding anything is so nice.
-这是一个很棒的地方-是的
- This is such a nice place. - Yes, it is.
我听说皮纳尔卡克是一个不错的地方，但我从未有机会参观
I've heard P?narcak was a nice place. But I never had the chance to visit.
-我想这里应该有瀑布-是的，我们会去的
-I think there is a waterfall here. -Yes, we'll go there too.
- 你好-你好
- Hello. - Hi.
-我们要两个房间-当然可以 请稍等
- We'd like two rooms. - Sure, just a second.
为什么不是一个房间？
Why not a single room?
你们有结婚证吗？
Do you have your marriage certificate with you?
我们是由伊玛目证婚的
We were married by Imam.
走廊里有摄像头
And there are cameras on hallways.
穆塔婚姻可以吗？
How about Muta marriage?
对不起 不行
I am sorry.
给你
Here.
小地方就是这样
That's what happens in small places.
不小，拥挤
Not small, crowded.
恐怕是的
I am afraid so.
如果可以的话，我想休息一个小时
If you excuse me, I'd like to take an hour's rest.
今天早上我很早起床，开车开得很累
I got up very early this morning and driving tired me out.
是的，当然可以 我可以去看看电子邮件
Yeah, sure. I can check my e-mails.
一小时后在楼下见面
Let's meet downstairs in one hour.
-好吧，再见-再见
- O.K, see you. - See you.
我当然记得你
Of course I remember you.
内斯林夫人的女儿 内芙拉·埃尔马斯
Mrs Nesrin's daughter, Nevra Elmas.
所以，你是来拜访老师了吗？
So, you came to see your teacher?
我听说你已经成为一名警察 恭喜你
I've heard that you've become a cop. Well done to you.
那么，你最近在忙些什么？你喜欢做警察吗？
So, what have you been up to? Do you like being a cop?
别提了
Don't ask.
真的很糟糕
It was really bad.
他们发现雷汉躺在草地上
They found Reyhan, laying on the grass.
你知道，他们在山上放牧的地方
You know, on the hill where they take the herds for grazing.
雷汉！
Reyhan!
来吧！
Come on!
雷汉等一等
Reyhan, wait.
我跟不上
I can't keep up.
谢谢
Thanks.
非常感谢你亲爱的
Thank you very much sweetheart.
你见过我的妻子吗？内芙拉
Have you met my wife Nevra?
没有 很高兴见到你
No. Pleased to meet you.
请用
Enjoy it.
那时我还年轻
I was a lot younger then.
天哪，我在说什么？
God, what was I talking about?
哦，是的，雷汉躺在草地上
Oh yes, Reyhan was laying on the grass.
她旁边有一瓶老鼠药
And there was a bottle of rat poison beside her.
天知道她是怎么得来的
God knows how she got hold of it.
那么聪明的女孩，是什么使她如此想不开？
Such a clever girl. What made her do such a thing?
我能说什么？
What can I say?
你永远不知道别人脑子里想的是什么
You never know what goes on in someone's head.
宾纳兹，过来 和我们坐一会吧
Binnaz, come over here. Sit with us darling.
不用了，我进屋去
No thanks. I'll be inside.
她真的很有才华
She was really talented.
她曾经写过很好的作品
She used to write great compositions.
她在学校起步较晚，但是她很聪明
She was a late starter at school. But she was really smart.
她很聪明 就像一颗钻石
She was very smart. She was like a diamond.
有才华
And talented.
她的亲人只有一个奶奶
She only had a granny.
没有其他了
She had nobody else.
并且她奶奶也去世了
And she passed away.
先生……
Well sir...
尽可能回想一下……
as far as you can remember...
你觉得雷汉有发生什么事吗？
do you think something might've happened to Reyhan...
在我们离开城镇后？
after we left town?
不，我认为没有
No, I don't think so.
据我所知，没有任何不对的事情
As far as I remember, there was no wrong doing.
但是她那时经常不来学校
But she was missing school as of late.
她一天在那里，但第二天却不在
She was there one day but not the next.
她的档案中说，由于严重抑郁而导致自杀是死亡的原因
Her file says cause of death is suicide due to heavy depression.
你有注意到吗？她沮丧吗？
Have you noticed anything? Was she depressed?
我记得，雷汉是一个开朗的女孩，笑容灿烂
As far as I remember, Reyhan was a cheerful girl with a big smile.
但不知道她内心深处发生了什么
But it is not possible to know what's been happening deep inside.
先生，我可以上厕所吗？
Sir, can I use the toilet?
这是什么？我是这么教你的吗？
What is this? Is this how I trained you?
你必须举手并先征得许可
You have to raise your hand and ask for permission first.
我在开玩笑
I was joking.
内芙拉，我只是在开玩笑
Nevra, my sweetheart. I was only joking.
去吧，宾纳兹会带你去
Go ahead. Binnaz will show you the way.
该死 我要迟到了
Damn! I'll be late.
你认识雷汉吗
Did you know Reyhan?
不认识
No.
我不是来自这里的
I am not from around here anyway.
我来自乡村
I've come from the village.
你什么时候来坎布拉的？
When did you come to Kambura?
我结婚后
After I got married.
我当时大约15岁，最后就这样了
I was around 15 years old. That's how I ended up here.
十五岁？
Fifteen?
当时塔欣先生多大了？
How old was Mr Tahsin at the time?
五十多岁
In his fifties.
我知道了
I see.
谢谢
Thanks.
你有话要告诉我吗？宾纳兹
Do you have something to tell me Binnaz?
我不认识那个女孩，雷汉，但是！
I don't know that girl, Reyhan, but...!
宾纳兹！
Binnaz!
你可以给我倒茶吗？
Can you pour me some tea?
我在这里很陌生 可能只有一年
I was new around here. May be only a year.
听说一个女孩子自杀了
I heard that a girl took her own life.
天啊！她听不到我说话吗？
God almighty! Can't she hear me?
宾纳兹 我让你来给我倒茶
Binnaz! I asked you to fill my glass.
宾纳兹！
Binnaz!
有一天，当他在学校的时候，一个女人突然出现了
One day, while he was at school a woman popped-by.
她说她是雷汉的奶奶
She said she was Reyhan's granny.
她说她在枕头里发现了一个笔记本
She said she found a notebook hidden inside her pillow.
她说：“她在这里写下了一切”
She said "she wrote down everything here".
“这可能揭示出她为何自杀的线索”
"This may reveal clues as to why she killed herself".
她为什么把笔记本带给你？
Why did she bring the notebook to you?
宾纳兹！
Binnaz!
她为什么把它带给你？
Why did she bring it to you?
因为她是文盲
She was illiterate.
她说：“把这个交给老师，他会知道该怎么做的”
She said "give this to the teacher, he'd know what to do with it".
那你做了什么？
And what did you do?
宾纳兹！
Binnaz!
我什么也没做我只是看了一眼
I didn't do anything. I just took a quick glance.
然后？
Then?
我把笔记本还给她，叫她去派出所
I gave it back to her and told her to take it to the police station.
她说她已经去了
She said she already did.
但是警察让她回去，说案件已经结案了
But the police had sent her away saying that the case is already closed.
我叫她去法院
I told her to go to the courthouse.
-笔记本里有什么？-我不知道
- What was in the notebook? - I don't know.
我当时也是文盲
I was illiterate at the time too.
你为什么叫她去法院
Why did you tell her to take it to the courthouse...
而不是将其移交给塔欣先生？
instead of handing it over to Mr.Tahsin?
我不想把那个可怜女孩的笔记本
I wasn't about to give the poor girl's notebook to a man...
给那个把孩子当成妻子的男人
who took a child as a wife.
他爱我，我们要结婚了
He loves me. We'll get married.
我要做新娘了
I'll be a bride.
你们在这里很久了
You two have been here for ages.
我一直在叫你给我倒茶
I have been asking you to pour me a cup of tea.
我死了你都不知道
You wouldn't have known if I died.
该死！
S... it!
我是哈姆扎
This is Hamza.
我是内芙拉 副警长
I am Nevra, the deputy chief.
我当然记得你
I sure recognize you. How can I not, anyway?
怎么会忘记那个把我抓回来的人呢？
How could you forget the one who put you away?
这次你想要什么？
What do you want this time?
你的兄弟塔亚尔提到过一个叫雷汉的女孩吗？
Has your brother Tayyar ever mentioned a girl named Reyhan?
来自坎布拉的14岁女孩 雷汉
A 14 year old from Kambura. Reyhan.
-你能听到我说话吗？哈姆扎？-能
-Can you hear me Hamza? -Yes, I can.
你是说雷汉吗？
Did you say Reyhan?
是的，雷汉
Yes, Reyhan.
对我有什么好处？
What's in it for me?
-你认识那个女孩吗？-我不认识
- Do you know the girl? - I don't.
但是，假设我听过这个名字
But let's say, I heard the name.
你能为我做什么？
What can you do for me?
我告诉你我会做什么，我会过去你那，把你关在单独的牢房里
I tell you what I'll do, I'll come over there, lock you in solitary confinement...
然后把钥匙让掉 怎么样？
and throw away the key. How about that?
小姐姐你脾气真大
You have such a quick temper, sis.
脾气暴躁的女人
Woman with a short fuse.
听着，我对这个叫雷汉的女孩不太了解
Look, I don't know much about this Reyhan girl.
这是我很久以来第一次听到这个名字
This is the first time I hear the name after a long time.
但是现在，我想起来了
But now, I remember.
塔亚尔醉酒时一直重复她的名字
Tayyar kept repeatingher name when he was stoned.
当我们问起女孩时，他曾经说过类似……
When we asked about the girl he used to say things like...
“可怜的女孩，他们糟蹋了她”这样的话
"poor girl, they wasted her".
他醒酒后，我们也问过他，但他不记得了
We used to ask him after he sobered up but he couldn't remember anything.
也许他记得，但是闭口不谈
Perhaps he remembered but avoided the subject with us.
你怎么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me anything?
当我问你泰雅是否强奸了任何人的时候……
When I've asked you if Tayyar raped anyone...
你为什么不提雷汉？
why didn't you mention Reyhan?
你好傻啊
You are so gullible sis.
塔亚尔是一个酒鬼 他喝醉了
Tayyar was an alcoholic. He was stoned.
他曾经说的是“他们浪费了她”，而不是“我浪费了她”
He used to say "they wasted her", not "I wasted her".
我告诉你……
I'll tell you what...
一个喝醉的男人可以做任何事情，但只有一件事不能做……
a drunken man can do anything except one thing...
他不能撒谎
he can't lie.
如果是他做的，他会告诉我们
If he got up to no good he would've told us.
这说明是别人做的
It means that somebody else did it.
那算什么啊？
So, what is it?
女孩死了，也已经结案了，不是吗？
The girl has gone and the case is closed, isn't it?
保持安静 塔亚尔
Keep quiet Tayyar.
为什么要安静？
Keep quiet for what?
她在光天化日下被糟蹋了
She was wasted in broad day-light.
可怜的雷汉被人糟蹋了
Poor Reyhan got wasted.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
你算什么男人？
Do you call yourselves men?
你想从那个可怜的女孩那里得到什么？
What did you want from the poor girl?
我听着呢
I am listening.
先生，这个车牌已经注销了
Sir, this plate is no longer registered.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
它在1998年从系统中删除，车辆报废
It was dropped from the system in 1998 and the vehicle was scrapped.
我知道了
I see.
-这是你的咖啡-谢谢妈妈
- Here is your coffee. - Thanks mum.
妈妈
Mum...
我觉得这里真的发生了坏事
I think really bad things happened here.
你是说被烧毁的房子吗？
Do you mean the burned house?
不，不是 我是说雷汉
No, not that. I mean Reyhan.
我觉得有人对她做了坏事
I think some people did very bad things to her.
-你在说什么？-我不知道
- What are you talking about? - I don't know.
但是不管发生什么事，坎布拉人都有责任
But whatever happened, people of Kambura are responsible.
你笑什么？
Why are you laughing?
怎么了？你在做什么？
What's going on? What are you doing?
你认识叫雷汉的人吗？
Do you know someone called Reyhan?
-谁，你说谁？-雷汉
- Who, who did you say? - Reyhan.
-内夫拉的同学-妈妈！
- Nevra's schoolmate. - Mum!
14岁时自杀的女孩
The girl who committed suicide when she was 14.
我发誓，我不认识她，我怎么会认识她？
I swear, I don't know her. How would I know her anyway?
听着，如果你隐瞒了什么……！
Look, if you're hiding anything...!
妈妈 冷静点 过来
Mum, calm down. Come here.
-天啊-冷静
- God almighty. - Calm down.
坐下
Sit down.
塞利姆叔叔
Uncle Selim...
你知道我的朋友雷汉……
you know my friend, Reyhan...
她真的发生了什么坏事
something really bad happened to her...
就在坎布拉
here in Kambura.
我不太确定
I am not too sure...
但是你知道凶手现在从坎布拉挑选受害者……
but you know the killer who picks victims from Kambura...
我认为他是在杀那些对雷汉犯下邪恶罪行的人
I think he kills the ones who did evil to Reyhan.
如果你对此有任何想法……
If you know anything about this or have an idea...
请告诉我 不要害怕
please tell me. Don't be afraid.
如果你什么都知道但不告诉我，那你才应该感到害怕
If you know anything but not telling me, that's when you should be afraid.
因为凶手最终也会找到你
Because the killer will eventually find you too.
我告诉过你，我什么都没做我只扔了一小块石头
I told you, I haven't done anything. I only threw a small piece of stone.
看着我 你这个畜生！
Look here, you b... stard!
快说！
Just spill the beans.
你说过他是出现幻觉了……
You said he was having dreams about it...
但以为是真实发生的，因为他没吃药
but thinking it was real because he was avoiding his medication.
值得吗？
Was it worth it?
值得你向我隐瞒吗？
Was it worth you hiding it from me?
你以为你隐藏了什么？
What did you think you were hiding? This?
你的丈夫用私刑杀人
That you had a husband who lynched people.
那有什么好处？
What good did that do?
你一点都不相信他
You don't trust him tiny bit.
以至于你相信他会对14岁的女孩做什么事情
So much so that you belive he would do something to 14 year old girl.
你甚至直接问他……
And you even asked him.
妈！
Mum!
为什么？
Why?
你为什么要成为那样的女人？
Why have you become the woman you are?
为什么要过这样的生活？
Why have such a life?
我什么都不知道
I don't know any other life.
我所知道的“立足，独立，坚强”
All I knew "Stand on your own feet, be independent, be strong..."
”你是一个孤儿”
you are an orphan".
“你有一个已故的丈夫”
"You have a deceased husband".
“还有一个小女孩在你的怀里”
"And a little girl in your arms".
永远不要跌倒 但是你怎么能不跌倒呢？
Don't ever fall. But how can you not?
你还年轻……
You are young, working...
要想办法谋生
trying to make a living.
但是你不是一个男人
But you are not a man.
你是一个女人
You are a woman.
希望你知道当我抱着你时你看我的眼神
Wish you knew how you used to look at me when I held you in my arms.
我被这个世界吓坏了 内芙拉
I was frightened of this world Nevra.
你必须要依靠一个男人
You have to hold on to a man.
当我试图找到一个合适的人时……
While trying to find the right one...
我自己成为了一个男人
I myself became a man.
我变成了男人
I turned into a man.
当你问我……
When you asked me...
为什么我向你隐瞒
why I hid it from you...
我怕自己一个人呆着
I was afraid to be left on my own...
如果他们把塞利姆带走
if they took Selim away.
我害怕独自一人
I was scared of being on my own.
我总是躲在男人后面
I always took cover behind men.
为了避免独自一人而被贴上“妓女”的标签
In order to avoid being alone and being labelled "whore".
但是你并不孤单
But you weren't alone.
你还有我
You had me.
一直都是
And you still have.
你怎么这么害怕
Why were you so scared?
我的小宝贝……
My little darling...
你以为雷汉为什么要结束自己的生命？
why do you think Reyhan took her own life?
该死！
F... ck!
-嗨 努赫特-嗨
- Nükhet, hi. - Hi.
你睡得好吗？
Did you have a nice sleep?
休息一个小时令人耳目一新
Having a rest for about an hour was refreshing.
我们去吃饭吧
Let's go and have a nice dinner.
这里一定有很多东西可以参观
There must be so many things to see here.
你曾经来过这里吗？
Have you ever been around this way?
没有 从没来过
No, never.
你看，这个小镇的名字真有趣 坎布拉
Look, such an interesting name for a town, Kambura.
为什么给你居住的地方起这样一个奇怪的名字？
Why give such a strange name to the place you live?
也许是别人给它??起的名字
Maybe, it was others who named it.
有意思
Very interesting.
-我为居民感到难过-是的
-I feel sorry for the residents. -Yes, yes.
总算联系到你了
Finally, I got hold of you.
会议刚刚结束
The meeting has only just finished.
安卡拉怎么样？夏天仍然炎热干燥吗？
How is Ankara? Still hot and dry in the summer?
必然是
It certainly is.
情况如何？你发现了什么吗？
What is the situation? Did you find anything?
我深入各部委，但无济于事
I digged into the ministries. But no avail.
得付些钱打点关系
You will have to cough up some dosh.
不，我告诉过你这是帮忙
No dosh, I told you it is a favour.
你说要帮忙，但索要的是黑市中最贵的物品
You say favour but asking for the most precious item in the black market.
我问了很多人 没人知道
I have asked million and one people. Nobody knows anything.
我们必须按相反的顺序
We have to go in reverse order.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我们将通过联系方式与关键人员保持联系
We'll get in touch with the key people through our contacts.
那我们就让他们说话
Then we'll make them talk.
我们不会直接问谁在处理你的案件
We are not going to ask who is messing with your case.
我们将相反
We'll do the opposite.
我们会用很多名字诱饵他们
We'll bait them with a lot of names...
谁应该干预案件
who supposedly interfering with the case.
我们就放线等待
We'll cast the line and wait.
-等待什么？-让官僚的自负取而代之
- Wait for what? - For bureaucratic ego to take over.
因为不管是在幕后发号施令的人还是那个看起来像中间人的人……
Because whoever is pulling the strings or acting like a middle man...
会被他们的自负击败并开始交待
will get beaten by his ego and begin to talk.
他会说“去尼玛的，我就是那个人”
He will say "f... ck off, I am the one".
这是个长远计划 这些人并不愚蠢
This is a long shot. These people are not stupid.
他们很蠢
They are stupid.
唯一可以让那些穿着相同西装的人
The only thing that sets those who wear the same style of suit...
分崩离析的方法就是吹嘘你在给谁走捷径
apart from one another is to brag about whose back you are scratching.
你在安卡拉一定很无聊
You must get really bored in Ankara.
因为夏天干热
It's because it's hot and dry here in the summer.
你什么都没吃
You haven't eaten anything.
我不饿妈妈
I am not hungry mum.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
试图弄清事情是什么时候开始的，
Trying to figure out when everything started and...
以什么顺序进行
in what order it progressed.
内芙拉！
Nevra!
你是否听说过一个叫塞米尔·哈夫兰的人？
Have you ever heard a man called Cemil Havran?
是的，那天我甚至和他通了电话
Yes. I even talked to him on the phone the other day.
他向你致以问候
He sent his regards to you.
我一直没机会告诉你，认为可能会伤害到塞利姆
I never got around to tell you, thinking they may harm Selim.
你还在隐藏什么吗？
Are you still hiding something mum?
这还不够秘密吗？
Isn't that enough of secrets?
我没有隐藏任何秘密，我现在告诉你
I am not hiding a secret or anything. I am telling you now.
塞米尔几乎拥有整个坎布拉
Cemil almost owns whole of Kambura.
没有他的话什么都办不成
Nothing ever takes place without his knowledge.
我想你最好和他谈谈
I think you'd better talk to him.
他是威胁塞利姆叔叔的人吗？
Was he the one who threatened Uncle Selim?
他不会自己做，而是要让他的小弟来做
He wouldn't do it himself. He would get his monkeys do it instead.
你认识乌拉尔，一直在闲逛的家伙
You know Vural, the guy who's been hanging around.
乌拉尔
Vural.
显然他警告塞利姆不要说起大火
Apparently he warned Selim not to talk about the fire.
我知道了
I see.
这意味着我们必须彻底改变坎布拉
It means we have to turn Kambura on its head.
不用担心我会跟他谈
Don't worry, I'll talk to him.
妈
Mum...
我们是1993年来到这里的，不是吗？
we came here in 1993, didn't we?
在这里住了一年
Stayed here for a year.
1994年
1994.
我记得是八月
I think it was August.
八月离开
Left in August.
雷汉有一个笔记本
Reyhan had a notebook.
如果它被藏在枕头下面
If it is as precious as to be hidden under a pillow...
它更可能是一本日记
it was more likely a diary.
那本日记现在在哪里？
Where is that diary now?
如果这些笔记是雷汉写的
If these notes were taken by Reyhan...
那么日记就在凶手那里
the killer has the diary.
假设她是在我生日那天写的
Let's assume that she wrote this on my birthday.
3月18日
March 18th.
内芙拉
Nevra...
雷汉给了你生日礼物吗？
has Reyhan given you a birthday present?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
[今天是内夫拉的生日] [我给她准备了礼物]
[It's Nevra's birthday today] [I got her a present].
-当我着手写这本书时-生活就是交通
- When I set out to write this book... - Life is Traffic.
我对事故做了很多研究
I did a lot of research on accidents.
-给你 先生-好
- Here you are sir. - Good.
-继续，打开门。-这可能会引起问题。
-Go on, open it. -It may cause a problem.
这个人自己就是问题 我就是解决问题的人
The guy himself is the problem. And I am here to solve it.
顺便说一句，他不会知道的 好吗？
By the way, he won't know about this. Am I clear?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
发生了一件事情 我永远不会忘记
There was an incident. I never forget it.
你还记得电视节目吗
Do you remember the TV show...
那个比赛
the contest...
参赛者聚集在汽车周围并把手放在汽车上
where contestants gather around a car and place their hands on it.
是的，我还记得他们以前在那个位置上度过了好几天
Yes, I remember it. They used to spend days in that position.
一个男人把手放在汽车上度过了37个小时
A man spent 37 hours with his hand on the car.
他把手放在车上，站在那里
He places his hand on the car and just stands there.
他是历时最长的人
He was the one who lasted the longest.
所以，他赢了车
So, he wins the car.
他把车开走了
He takes the car away...
在上路的第一天，他卷入了一场可怕的事故
and on his very first day on the road he gets involved in a horrific accident.
卡车撞到驾驶员侧的轿厢
A truck hits the car on the driver's side.
真的很糟糕
That is really bad.
还有
And there is more.
你知道发生了什么吗？
Do you know what happens?
他失去了右手，那只他曾经用来摸汽车37小时的右手
He loses his right hand, the one he used to touch the car for 37 hours.
你认为这件事含义吗？
Do you think it has a meaning?
如果有含义，那是什么含义？
And if there is a meaning, what is it?
那家伙现在在哪里？
Where is that guy now?
他们曾说到晚餐
They were talking about having dinner.
这条路的尽头只有一个吃饭的地方
There is only one place to eat around here which is at the end of the road.
好，很好
O.K, fine. Thanks.
我今天遇到一个女孩，她叫内芙拉·埃尔马斯
I met a girl today. Her name is Nevra Elmas.
她是我唯一信任的人，因为内芙拉了解我
She is the only one I trust. Because Nevra understands me.
今天是内夫拉的生日，我给她准备了礼物
It's Nevra's birthday today. I got her a present.
我和费夫拉分享了一个秘密
Me and Nevra share a secret.
你真的吻了吗？
Did you really kiss?
你答应不告诉任何人
You promised not to tell anyone.
我们当然吻了
Of course we kissed.
向上帝发誓？
Swear to God?
你都不相信 我告诉过你很多次
You don't believe anything. I told you so many times.
我把一切都告诉了内芙拉，但她不相信我
I told Nevra everything. But she doesn't believe me.
我不吃水果
I don't eat fruit.
因为当水果中的糖与酒精反应时
Because when the sugar in fruit gets in reaction with alcohol...
会变成脂肪
it turns into fat.
手拿开
Move your hand.
雷汉
Reyhan.
谁记得？
Who remembers?
塔亚尔！
Tayyar!
塔亚尔记得你
Tayyar remembers you.
他说：“他们糟蹋了那个可怜的女孩”
He said "they wasted the poor girl".
如果塔亚尔还记得的话
If Tayyar remembers so do the others.
他们所有人，他们一定都记得
All of them, they all remember.
整个坎布拉都记得
Whole of Kambura remembers.
他们只是假装自己不知道
They just pretend that they don't.
我在跟谁说话？
Who am I speaking to?
肯定不是在跟你身在安其拉的朋友说话
Not to your friend in Ankara.
这是肯定的
That's for sure.
我也觉得你不应该再再跟他说话
I don't think you should speak to him again either.
救他一命 也救你自己一命
Save his a..ss and save your own.
继续做你擅长的事情 写几页文章
Stick to what you know. Write 3rd page articles.
因为当你翻报纸时……
Because as you turn the pages in a newspaper...
你翻到有关政治问题的页面……
you come to the pages with political issues...
那就发生了微妙的变化
and that's where the scenery changes.
你最后很可能会被关进监狱
You may end up being locked up.
当你要证明自己无罪的时候……
And when it comes to trying to prove your innocence...
审判将持续至少一年
the trial would last at least a year.
对自己好一点
Have mercy on yourself.
好吗？
O.K?
不要让自己与复杂的企业纠缠在一起
Don't get yourself mixed up with complicated businesses.
因为下次电话响起时，不会再警告你
Because next time that phone rings, it won't be for a warning.
如果你准备好了 我们就走吧
We can leave if you're ready.
这条路
This way.
怎么了？
What is it?
警察 不要碰任何东西
Police. Don't touch anything.
好
O.K.
我们以前也喝酒
We used to drink wine too.
但是喝最便宜的
But the cheapest one.
它被称为“狗杀手”吗？ 你听说过吗？
It was called the "dog killer". Have you heard of it?
你知道标签上写了什么吗？
Do you know what was written on the label?
（拉丁语）In vino veritas.
In vino veritas.
我们以前很想知道这是什么意思
We used to wonder what it meant.
这是什么意思？
What does it mean?
酒醉吐真言
The truth is hidden in the wine.
-别管我-来吧
- Leave me alone. - Come on.
-畜生！-走吧
- B... stards! - Come on.
放开我 我自己会走
Leave me alone. I can find my own way.
该死的吉普赛人！
F... cking gypsy!
他真是个大嘴巴
He's got such a big mouth.
他认为他可以接管这个地方
He thinks he can take over the place.
我知道你不喜欢吉普赛人
I know you don't like gypsies.
我恨死他们了
I f..cking hate them.
我爸爸说他们应该滚去别的地方
My dad says they should f... ck off somewhere else.
但只是说说不够，乌福克
But saying is not enough Ufuk.
看看他是怎么强迫我们
Look how he forces himself on us.
最好的办法就是等他上床了，让那畜生被烧成灰烬
Best thing to do is set his bed alight. Let the b... stard burn to ashes.
他是一个行走的酒瓶
He is a walking alcohol bottle.
只需一点火花就足以点燃他
Just one spark would be enough to blow him up.
但是我们需要一个英雄去行动
But we need a hero to do the deed.
看看你周围
Look around you.
每个人都安静地坐着 尾巴夹在腿中间
Everybody is sitting all quiet, tails between their legs.
他还不如往他们脸上吐唾沫呢
He might've as well spat on their faces.
我们需要一个人来解决他
We need someone to sort him out.
我会做的
I'll do it.
我发誓我能做到
I swear I can do it.
我将把吉普赛人烧死，让他们甚至都不敢再回到坎布拉
I will burn that gypsy so bad they will ever dare to return to Kambura.
这才像个男子汉
Now, this is the man talking.
来吧，干杯
Come on, bottoms up.
你为什么给我打电话？
Why are you calling me?
这大半夜的你想要什么？
What do you want from me in the middle of the night?
是的，德瓦告诉我了
Yes, Deva told me.
好，寄离婚文件过来我会签
O.K, just send the divorce papers. I will sign them.
你是什??么意思 改变主意了？
What do you mean you changed your mind?
你怎么可以这样？你认为这是一个游戏吗？
How can you? Do you think this is a game?
不，我不要你来土耳其
No, I don't want you to come to Turkey.
我无话可说
I have nothing to say to you.
婚姻结束了 我们之间什么都没有
The marriage is over. There is nothing between us.
永远不要再打给我
Don't ever call me again.
是谁，这么晚了打电话？
Who was it, calling this time at night?
德瓦
Deva.
他在找东西，但找不到
He was looking for something but couldn't find it.
打电话问我
Called to ask me.
我觉得他还是没找到
I don't think he found it.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
-非常感谢 努赫特-谢我什么？
- Thank you very much Nükhet. - What for?
我好久没有感到这种平静了
I haven't felt this peaceful for ages.
而你就是原因
And you are the reason.
我觉得我能长生不老了
I feel like I am going to live forever.
我感觉就像我和你你将永远坐在这里，看星星
I feel like me and you will be sitting here, watching the stars forever.
仿佛永远不会结束
As if it will never end.
不会结束的 阿加
It will not end Agah.
我们每次想到这里时都可以将这个夜晚重温
We will relive tonight every time we think about it.
星空下
Under the stars.
只要我们记得
As long as we remember.
那是诗人所说的
That's what the poet said.
生命是一种回忆 你忘记了就会死
Life is a memory. You'll die when you forget.
还真是这样，是谁说的？
So true. Who said it?
我忘了
I forgot.
我洗了他
I washed him.
我很肯定我洗了
Sure I washed him.
我洗了图凡的尸体 他们找不到任何证据
I washed Tufan. They can't find any evidence.
我记得的 你看？
I remembered. See?
你这肮脏的骗子 我洗了他
You dirty crooks. I washed him.
好吧，现在我醒过来了……！
Well, now that I am awake...!
不在这里，怎么会忘记呢？
It's not here. How could you forget it?
你怎么会忘记带枪？
How could you forget it?
在这里等我 我马上回来
Wait here. I'll be right back.
-你去哪里了？-我现在来了 不是吗？
- Where have you been? - I am here aren't I?
你有没有告诉你父亲我们要结婚了？
Did you tell your dad that we are going to get married?
不，我还没有机会，但我还有其他事情要告诉你
No, I didn't have the chance. But I have something else to tell you.
还记得我告诉过你我有一个兄弟吗？塞米尔
Remember I told you I have a brother? Cemil.
是的 我知道
Yes, that's the one.
他说：“现在雷汉已经吻了你，她会吻我吗？”
He said "now that Reyhan kissed you, would she kiss me too".
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
等等
Wait.
他说他会告诉所有人，人们都将知道你的名字
He said he will tell everybody, people will be calling you names...
我们就不能结婚了
and we won't be able to get married.
你好 雷汉
Hello Reyhan.
你好吗？
How are you?
大清早的这是怎么回事？
What's going on here so early in the morning?
[你还记得我吗？]
[Do you remember me?]